sharebloc.com 2014-09-20

# ShareBloc - A community for professionals

Effective September 21, 2012

Welcome to ShareBloc, the service of ShareBloc, Inc. ("ShareBloc," "we," or "us"). Our Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, disclose, and protect information that applies to our Service, and your choices about the collection and use of your information.

Click on the links below to jump to each section:

Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given to them in our [Terms of Use](http://www.sharebloc.com/terms.php).

We collect the following types of information about you:

We ask for certain information such as your username, first and last name, phone number, e-mail address, job title, employer, and other work-related information when you register for a ShareBloc account, or if you correspond with us. We may also retain any messages you send through the Service, and may collect information you provide in User Content you post to the Service. We use this information to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service.

We may receive information about you from third parties. For example, if you access our websites or Service through a third-party connection or log-in, for example, through LinkedIn, by "following," "liking," adding the ShareBloc application, linking your account to the ShareBloc Service, etc., that third party may pass certain information about your use of its service to ShareBloc. This information could include, but is not limited to, the user ID associated with your account (for example, your LinkedIn UID), an access token necessary to access that service, any information that you have permitted the third party to share with us, and any information you have made public in connection with that service. If you allow us access to your contacts list, your contacts' user IDs, and your connection to those contacts, may be used and stored to make your experience more social, and to allow you to invite your contacts to use our Service as well as provide you with updates if and when your contacts join ShareBloc. You should always review, and if necessary, adjust your privacy settings on third-party websites and services before linking or connecting them to the ShareBloc Service. You may also unlink your third party account from the Service by adjusting your settings on the third party service. If you unlink your third party account, we will remove the information collected about you in connection with that service.

If you choose, you can locate your contacts with ShareBloc accounts through our "Find contacts" feature. The "Find contacts" feature allows you to choose to locate contacts either through (i) your contact list, (ii) social media sites (such as LinkedIn) or (iii) through a search of names and usernames on ShareBloc. If you choose to find your contacts through your contact list, then you agree to provide ShareBloc access to your contact list such that we can perform the search necessary to determine whether or not someone associated with the information you provide is using ShareBloc. If you choose to find your contacts through social media sites, then you understand that the information these sites provide to use to conduct this type of search is governed by their privacy policies and your account settings on those sites. If you choose to find your contacts through a search of names or usernames then simply type a name to search and see if that name or username appears on our Service. Note that we do not retain any information contained in your contacts list, or information from social media sites about your contacts, and we do not use such information for any purpose other than to help you find your contacts on ShareBloc.

We may directly collect analytics data, or use third-party analytics tools, to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Service. These tools collect information sent by your browser, including the pages you visit and other information that assists us in improving the Service. We collect and use this analytics information in aggregate form such that it cannot reasonably be manipulated to identify any particular individual user.

When you visit the Service, we may send one or more cookies - a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets ShareBloc help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the site. A cookie may also convey information to us about how you use the Service (e.g., the pages you view, the links you click and other actions you take on the Service), and allow us or our business partners to track your usage of the Service over time. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser's directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access the Service. When you use our Service, our servers automatically record certain log file information. These server logs may include anonymous information such as your web request, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with links on the Service, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

When you use the Service, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to anonymously track the online usage patterns of our Users. In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened and which links are clicked by recipients. The information allows for more accurate reporting and improvement of the Service.

When you access the Service by or through your device, we may access, collect, monitor and/or remotely store one or more "device identifiers," such as a universally unique identifier ("UUID"). Device identifiers are small data files or similar data structures stored on or associated with your device, which uniquely identify your device. A device identifier may be data stored in connection with the device hardware, data stored in connection with the device's operating system or other software, or data sent to the device by ShareBloc. A device identifier may convey information to us about how you browse and use the Service. A device identifier may remain persistently on your device, to help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the Service. Some features of the Service may not function properly if use or availability of device identifiers is impaired or disabled.

When you access the Service by or through your device, we may access, collect, monitor and/or remotely store "location data," which may include GPS coordinates (e.g. latitude and/or longitude) or similar information regarding the location of your device. Location data may convey to us information about how you browse and use the Service. Some features of the Service, particularly location-based services, may not function properly if use or availability of location data is impaired or disabled.

We use the information we collect or receive to communicate directly with you. We may send you emails containing newsletters, promotions and special offers. If you do not want to receive such email messages, you will be given the option to opt out or change your preferences. We also use your information to send you Service-related emails (e.g., account verification, purchase and billing confirmations and reminders, changes/updates to features of the Service, technical and security notices). You may not opt out of Service-related e-mails.

We use or may use cookies, log file, device identifiers, location data, clear gifs information, information provided by you, and User Content to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) to provide and monitor the effectiveness of our Service; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns; (e) diagnose or fix technology problems; (f) help you efficiently access your information after you sign in; (g) to provide advertising to your browser or device; (h) automatically update the ShareBloc application on your device, and (i) create business reports and pamphlets for purchase based on anonymized data.

We will not rent or sell your information to third parties outside ShareBloc and its group companies (including any parent, subsidiaries and affiliates) without your consent, except as noted below:

We may share your information with third-party business partners for the purpose of providing the Service to you. Those business partners will be given limited access to your information as is reasonably necessary to deliver the Service, and we will require that such third parties comply with this Privacy Policy.

Any information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Service, such as User Content, becomes available to the public, as controlled by any applicable privacy settings. To change your privacy settings on the Service, please change your Account Page settings. Subject to your profile and privacy settings, any User Content that you make public is searchable by other Users. If you remove information that you posted to the Service, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Service, or if other Users have copied or saved that information.

We may buy or sell/divest/transfer the company (including any shares in the company), or any combination of its products, services, assets and/or businesses. Your information such as customer names and email addresses, User Content and other user information related to the Service may be among the items sold or otherwise transferred in these types of transactions. We may also sell, assign or otherwise transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, acquisitions, bankruptcies, dissolutions, reorganizations, liquidations, similar transactions or proceedings involving all or a portion of the company.

ShareBloc will disclose your information where required to do so by law or subpoena or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) to enforce our Terms of Use http://www.sharebloc.com/terms.php or to protect the security or integrity of our Service; and/or (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of ShareBloc, our Users or others.

We may share certain service type information, including information obtained through tools such as cookies, log files, device identifiers, location data and clear gifs (such as anonymous usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with our third-party business partners for the purposes described in the section above on "How We Collect and Use Information." We may also aggregate or otherwise strip data of all personally identifying characteristics and may share that aggregated, anonymized data with third parties.

Among other services, ShareBloc provides you with information on various vendors and the reviews, ratings, and recommendations that our Users have posted about vendors. The information that Users provide help our ShareBloc community to locate quality vendors for a User's specific need. Simply, your feedback helps other Users. The type of information that you share with other Users can be controlled by you through your Account Page. Any information that you post under the "public" setting can be seen and used by anyone through the Service, and you understand that we can use this information to create reports, pamphlets, and other types of media to share with third parties or for any other purpose. Any information that you post under the "custom" setting will only be shared with the individuals or groups to whom you allow access. You understand that we can use the information under the "custom" setting to create reports, pamphlets and other types of media to share with third parties, but we will do so on an anonymized basis. Any information that you post under the "anonymous" setting will be kept anonymous, and you understand that sharing will be limited to anonymized User Content and other aggregated anonymized data.

We may also share certain information such as your location, browser and cookie data and other data relating to your use of our Service with our business partners to deliver advertisements ("ads") that may be of interest to you. ShareBloc may allow third-party ad servers or ad networks to serve advertisements on the Service. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the ads and ad links that appear on the Service, and will automatically receive your IP address when they do so. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, device identifiers, location data, and clear gifs, see above) to compile information about your browser's or device's visits and usage patterns on the Service, and to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize the advertising content. ShareBloc does not sell, rent, or share the information we collect directly from you or about you from third parties with these third-party ad servers or ad networks for such parties' own marketing purposes.

Please note that an advertiser may ask ShareBloc to show an ad to a certain audience of Users (e.g., based on demographics or other interests). In that situation, ShareBloc determines the target audience and ShareBloc serves the advertising to that audience and only provides anonymous aggregated data to the advertiser. If you respond to such an ad, the advertiser or ad server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach.

The ShareBloc Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, third-party advertisers. Please consult the respective privacy policies of such advertisers or contact such advertisers for more information.

Your information collected through the Service may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which ShareBloc or its subsidiaries, affiliates, or service providers maintain facilities. ShareBloc may transfer information that we collect about you, including personal information, to affiliated entities, or to other third parties across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. If you are located in the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that we may transfer information, including personal information, to a country and jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction, and you consent to the transfer of information to the U.S. or any other country in which ShareBloc or its parent, subsidiaries, affiliates, or service providers maintain facilities and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy.

ShareBloc cares about the security of your information and uses commercially reasonable safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of all information collected through the Service. To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from ShareBloc, at all times. However, ShareBloc cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to ShareBloc or guarantee that information on the Service may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed. Your privacy settings may also be affected by changes to the functionality of third party sites and services that you add to the ShareBloc Service, such as social networks. ShareBloc is not responsible for the functionality or security measures of any third party.

In the event that any information under our control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, ShareBloc will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and where appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other steps, in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations.

You may update your account information and email-communication preferences at any time by logging in to your account and changing your Account Page. You can also stop receiving promotional email communications from us by clicking on the "unsubscribe link" provided in such communications. We make every effort to promptly process all unsubscribe requests. As noted above, you may not opt out of Service-related communications (e.g., account verification, purchase and billing confirmations and reminders, changes/updates to features of the Service, technical and security notices). If you have any questions about reviewing or modifying your account information, you can contact us directly at [support@sharebloc.com](mailto:support@sharebloc.com).

Please refer to your browser's technical information for instructions on how to delete and disable cookies and other tracking/recording tools. Note that disabling cookies and/or other tracking tools prevents ShareBloc or its business partners from tracking your browser's activities in relation to the Service, and for use in targeted advertising activities by third parties. However, doing so may disable many of the features available through the Service. If you have any questions about opting out of the collection of cookies and other tracking/recording tools, you can contact us directly at [support@sharebloc.com.](mailto:support@sharebloc.com)

Following termination or deactivation of your User account, ShareBloc may retain your profile information and User Content for a commercially reasonable time for backup, archival, or audit purposes.

ShareBloc does not knowingly collect or solicit any information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register as Users. The Service and its content are not directed at children under the age of 13. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [support@sharebloc.com.](mailto:support@sharebloc.com)

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites or services linked to or from the Service, including the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, our Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party websites or services. Your browsing and interaction on any third-party website or service, including those that have a link or advertisement on our website, are subject to that third party's own rules and policies. In addition, you agree that we are not responsible and we do not control over any third-parties that you authorize to access your User Content. If you are using a third-party website or service (like LinkedIn) and you allow such a third-party access to you User Content you do so at your own risk. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources other than through the Service.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the Service, please contact us at [support@sharebloc.com.](mailto:support@sharebloc.com)

ShareBloc may modify or update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect the changes in our business and practices, and so you should review this page periodically. When we change the policy in a material manner we will let you know and update the 'last modified' date at the bottom of this page.

This Agreement was last modified on September 21, 2012.
